IMAD AZTOUT

Casablanca, Morocco. Mobile: +212 663 106 957

E-mail: Imad aztout@hotmail.com



PROFIL

Sales professional, with 16 years of experience selling IT solutions (hard, soft and services), including management and channel development in South Europe, North, West and Central Africa. Comfortable in complex negotiations, I have experience in creating and managing profitable businesses, establishing and maintaining relationships with excellent levels of retention and loyalty. Good communication and leader-ship skills. I'm oriented solutions and results. Excellent references available on request.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE Consulting - Business Development Manager, Morocco. From 07/2019 to current day.

- Consulting, Integration & business dev. w/ customers, partner & distributors (Network, DC, Security, UCC)
- I accompany my clients on the choice of solutions and partners to optimize the cost and treatment times.
- I manage the entire sales cycle, from cold call to closing.

HIPERDIST ALLIANCE - Sales Manager, Morocco. From 01/2019 to 07/2019

- Insure that the business meets and exceeds all targets for sales, reseller management, and satisfaction across vendors. Cisco, NetApp, CMVLT, Avaya, Palo-Alto, VMware, Oracle, Alibaba Cloud, Microsoft.
- Supervising, guiding and motivating a sales team, presales, operations, credit, logistic and marketing.

FINATECH - Business Development Manager, North WCA. From 01/2018 to 12/2018.

- Consulting, Integration & Bus. Dev. with customers, distributors and manufacturers (Network, DC, Security, UCC)
- Manage the entire customer relationship: understand the mapping of the account, advise the client, build a strong and solid partnership and a relationship of trust, follow-up w/ partners (distributors & constructors)

GTI Software & Networking - Business Development Manager, Morocco. From 01/2017 to 01/2018.

- Develop business relationships with value added resellers & IT Integrators. Launch SALICRU distribution.
- Recruit new partners for GTI, manage all aspects of the sales process from cold calling to closing.

WESTCON COMSTOR - Regional Sales Manager, North Africa. From 12/2013 to 12/2016.

- Ensure that the business meets and exceeds all targets for sales, reseller management and satisfaction across all vendors. Security, Data center, UCC, Networking & Services (Cisco, SolarWinds, Imagicle, Panduit, F5, NetApp, Arbor, Palo Alto, Checkpoint, Juniper, Extreme, Ruckus, VMware, Veeam, Kaspersky ...)
- Responsible for the overall coordination, functional management, and lead sales activities of all Vendors trough a team of 15 persons. Sales, Presales, Marketing, Operations and Logistics.

CISCO - Business Manager, WCA. From 02/2013 to 12/2013.

- Drive business through distributors and partners in West and Central Africa territory.
- Establish direct relationships with partners to maximize revenue opportunities and positioning Cisco Solutions (Hard, Soft and Service).

INTELCIA - Team Leader. From 09/2012 to 02/2013.

Outsourcing. Drive day to day Activity by phone and emails through a team of 15 agents.

DELL From 05/2004 to 06/2012.

- Sales Manager. 15 Sales rep. direct reports, Online- offline, Consumer, Small & Medium Business, French market
- Technical Sales Rep. Presales, Server & Storage, Small & Medium Business. Frenchmarket
- Large Opportunity Rep. Project manager for Small & Medium Business. Spanish market.
- Sales Engineer for Small & Medium Business. Spanish market.

EDUCATION

2002-2004: 2nd Cycle, Management at *Institut des Hautes Etudes Economiques et Sociales*, IHEES. Brussels - Casablanca.

2000-2002: 11st Cycle, Management at Institut des Hautes Etudes Economiques et Sociales, IHEES. Brussels - Casablanca.

1999-2000: University Orientation Course, à IES Ávila, Spain.

1998-1999: Bachelor, at Spanish Institute Juan Ramon Jimenez, Casablanca, Morocco

LANGUAGES